<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="02B0C849-FF6D-4C0F-AA5C-4987A3B1BBC8">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20140701" date="2014-07-01 20:29:47 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>22-Pistepirkko @ Pushkin</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Last night I went to the Pushkin club in Dresden with my Finnish pal Mira to see, yes indeed, a Finnish band called 22-Pistepirkko (translates as 22 spotted lady bird... good name... why can&#x2019;t I think of one like that...?)&#xD;&#xD;They have been around for donkeys years, since the early 80&#x2019;s in fact, and thus have a solid grounding in new wave punk, and proved that with a couple of great short pop punk blasts. But, by no means was it all like that. They took us through modern electronic loops, Farsia Organ lead pop rock (in fact much akin to the Inspiral Carpets in one song), slow moody textures, and even psychedelia at the end before the encores, of which there were one and a half. &#xD;&#xD;Being me, I seemed to prefer the faster louder more guitarry songs that were clearly from earlier in their career, but the rest of it was pretty good too, and the three old fellas put on a rather impressive show.  &#xD;&#xD;They have a new album out, and all that...&#xD;see http://www.22-pistepirkko.net/biography.html&#xD;&#xD;The support band, The Craftclub Houseband, put on a good show too, and created a nice racket with bass drums, two acoustics and female (nice and husky) and make voices. Billed as jazz rock... I wouldn&#x2019;t have called it that, but would also struggle to categorize it. Probably folk rock really. &#xD;&#xD;The drummer was an entertaining combination of stick insect and hippy, who at first seemed awkward, but then quickly convinced me he knew what he was going, and proceeded to give the skins a very admirable bashing despite looking like he wasn&#x2019;t built for it. The female guitarist vocalist carried the other singer, who was clearly less talented and original. They would have been better as a 3some. She was very good, and the bassist held his own. &#xD;&#xD;After the day&#x2019;s shopping marathon (light shades, food and a new guitar!) my feet conked out at the end, so we had a nice sit down in the disco room in Pushkin, which had sand on the floor (why!!!?) but a nice little atmos all the same. Cool gig venue / club that Pushkin place is... I jsut wish it was 500 meters closer to my house. It&#x2019;s a bit of a stroll.</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Saturday, April 5, 2008&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="5_22-Pistepirkko_%40_Pushkin_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="400px" height="300px"/>
</content>
