<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="02B0C849-FF6D-4C0F-AA5C-4987A3B1BBC8">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20140701" date="2014-07-01 20:29:37 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>That&#x2019;s some jolly cold weather...</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Minus 30 degrees Celsius is 12 oC colder than your average domestic freezer. At that temperature what little moisture is left in the air tends to freeze out into tiny ice crystals that get trapped in the temperature inversion close to the ground. Add clear skies and the low winter sun to that, and hey presto, one of nature&#x2019;s little wonders, the ice-bow, above. Doesn&#x2019;t happen very often, but it did today and yesterday. &#xD;&#xD;Lots of other interesting things happen in these arctic conditions. The blocks of compacted snow on the side of the road left by the ploughs are frozen so hard that they make a clinking sound like blocks of cinder when you kick them. Outside, things generally sound odd, as the air is so cold and dense, noises travel funny. Touching metal objects with bare flesh will probably result in a trip to the hospital for skin grafts. You are suddenly eternally grateful for all the horrible looking but very cosy hats, gloves, mittens, scarves, wooly jumpers and socks your gran knitted you.  &#xD;&#xD;Getting the car going in the morning is another unique experience. Forget just pitching up, opening the door, jumping in and setting off. There are several hurdles to jump prior to safe departure. Firstly, you have to unplug the electricity supply from the heater element that keeps the oil in the sump somewhat liquid, such that the starter motor is able to turn the engine over and start it. If you have an older car, and no engine heater, then forget attempting to start it until spring. Next you have to open the door, normally a simple process. However, in these temperatures, if you have neglected to lubricate the lock, you have little hope of getting the key to turn until you manage to defrost it. No mean feat that. Watch out for Dumb and Dumber style tongue frozen to metal syndrome as you try to blow warm air into the key hole. Once the lock is disengaged, you have to open the door by first freeing up the frozen latch, then carefully persuading the door to open without ripping off the rubber seal which is frozen hard to the door. Great, you are inside the car! Sadly the exercise is only just starting. &#xD;&#xD;Now you have to start it. When I got my tiny English battery changed in our old Golf  (after leaving the lights on for the umpteenth time), they guy laughed out loud at its diminutive dimensions. The one he put in was twice as powerful. Its all about &#x201C;cold cranking power&#x201D; apparently. As you turn the key in the ignition, you hear the unpleasant noise of the oil-turned-to-tar failing miserably to lubricate the moving parts in the engine block, while the starter motor strains to turn them over. If you are lucky the engine will spring into life, emanating impressive clouds of white smoke/condensation from the exhaust. If you are less lucky, you might be treated to further upsetting mechanical noises until your battery expires. &#xD;&#xD;With the engine alive, its now time to defrost! So its fan on full to windscreen, heater on full, and rear screen heater very much on. At this point you could wait an hour or so until the rock hard layer of ice on both the outside and the inside of all the windows has melted enough for you to see where you are going. Most people don&#x2019;t have time to wait for that, so unfortunately its time to grab the combined snow brush / ice scraper and once more venture outside of the safe confines of your vehicle, into the arctic. Having brushed off any snow that has very rudely decided to settle on the car, you meet the almost impenetrable ice coating your finest Pilkington automotive glass.&#xD;&#xD;Since there is warm air (ok, its still below freezing at the moment, until the engine warms up a bit) blowing on the windscreen, and the heater element is taking care of the back screen, you are left with the layer of dried superglue covering the side windows and mirrors. Removal of this requires much more effort than a casual scrape with a library card. No, we are talking leverage, extreme pressure, repeated jabbing, hacking, grinding and swearing. At this point you begin to rue your poor decision to leave your proper gloves at home, because you wouldn&#x2019;t need them since you would be driving today. After some minutes of hard labour, both mirrors and all the side windows are clear of ice, on the outside at least, so you turn your attention to the now partially softened ice on the windscreen and back screen. Hopefully you remembered to lift up the windscreen wipers the night before, otherwise they will be frozen firmly to the glass, and any attempt to free them in order to clean the screen will result in you ripping the wiper blade edges off, rendering them worse than useless. &#xD;&#xD;OK, ready to go! Ummm, no, not quite... After getting back into the car, and spending a few minutes unfreezing the door latch back into normal position such that the door will shut and stay closed, you are still faced with translucent, but definitely not transparent ice covering the inside of all the windows. You have choices. Attempt to scrape it off, or put the radio on and wait for the hot air blower to do its job. Scraping it with the big scraper doesn&#x2019;t work because its impossible to efficiently scrape a concave surface with a flat edge, you only remove ice from thin stripes either end of the edge. In attempting this you also cause a blizzard of snow inside the car and leave numerous grubby marks over the inside of the windscreen which seem impossible to remove even in the summer with brand new windowlene. I have been using the second method. After songs by Lynnard Skynnard, Phil Collins, Kiss and some Finnish 80&#x2019;s rock band that sound quite good but you don&#x2019;t know what they are singing about apart from the chorus which is in Finglish and appears to be about &#x201C;Rocking the Hardest&#x201D;, you can see out of the front, and see part of the mirrors. The heater element is still struggling with the ice on the back screen, but thin lines are clearing. Side windows? You don&#x2019;t really need those, so you disengage the hand brake, and if you are lucky the rear brakes are not frozen, and you can reverse out without the frightening cracking noise of the brake pads ripping free of the drums. Changing gears is a bit like trying to mix cheese with a spade since the gear box oil has crystalised solid, but it gets better after a mile or two. Well done, you have managed to set off!&#xD;&#xD;In the event of the car failing to start, you may find yourself walking to work, unless you sensibly decide to stay in the warm at home. Even after a short walk, you feel the ligaments in your knees start to stiffen, and every deep breath results in frozen nostrils and the need to cough. Its a whole new kind of cold, as opposed to the wet windy cold of Whitby or Hartelpool, or a cold shower, or the swimming in the hole in the ice kind of cold. Like the Inuit of the arctic have many words for different kinds of snow, we really need different names for all these different forms of low temperature discomfort. For -30 oC outside, I propose &#x201C;Brrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrr&#x201D;.&#xD;&#xD;The city blokes finally got chance to make the ice skating track on the lake, as its only been cold enough for the lake to freeze deep enough to carry the weight of the snow plough in the last few weeks. However, now its too cold to go skating, skiing, or even walking too far without thermal undies, 3 pairs of socks, 2 hats, 2 pairs of gloves, three scarves and four coats. Think Michelin Man - the show - on ice.&#xD;&#xD;Still, no need to panic, its only going to be -15 oC tomorrow, which will feel positively toasty, and might even be skating weather...</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Wednesday 7 February 2007&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
